Guide to the Vassar College Women's Studies Program Records, 1977-2007
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Women's Studies Program Records
1970-2007
1980-2002
Vassar College Women's Studies Program
5.8 cubic feet (7 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials documenting the history of the Vassar College Women's Studies Program from its founding in 1977 to 2007.
Administrative History
Since at least 1971 faculty, students, and trustees had advocated the creation of a Women's Studies Program. Not until 1977, however, was the first interdepartmental Women's Studies course added to the College curriculum. The following year a major in Women's Studies was introduced under the auspices of the Independent Program, a major that drew upon courses from a variety of departments. Women's Studies became a separate multidisciplinary concentration in 1986. From 1988 to 1998 the program continued to add new multidisciplinary courses to its curriculum. In 2002-2003 the program began offering a 12-credit multidisciplnary major and a 6-credit correlate sequence.
See Ronald D. Patkus and Elizabeth A. Daniels, eds., An Administrative History of Vassar College, 1861-2003, Poughkeepsie: Vassar College, 2004, p. 62.
Scope and Content Note
Materials documenting the history of the Vassar College Women's Studies Program from its founding in 1977 to 2007. Includes memos, budgets, correspondence, notes, newsletters, grant proposals, course materials, and publicity materials.
Access
Some materials in Series I are restricted due to personnel privacy issues. Please consult the archivist for further information. The remainder of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Curricula
Subjects:
Women's studies--Curricula--United States; Women's studies--New York (State)
VCL Categories
Vassar College Academic Departments and Programs
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, October 2011. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, January 2023.
Acquisition Information
Collection transfered from the Women's Studies Program office, 2008.
Series List
- Series I. ADMINISTRATIVE FILES AND CORRESPONDENCE, (Boxes 1-2)
  Annual reports, correspondence, Steering Committee files, mailing lists, and other materials relating to the administration of the program. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series II. CURRICULUM, (Boxes 2-3)
  Course lists, syllabi, student handbook information, and other materials relating to the program curriculum. Arranged alphabetically with general curriculum files preceding those for individual courses.
- Series III. EVENTS, (Boxes 3-4)
  Film screening announcements, conference announcements, agendas for "First Friday" gatherings and other materials relating to program events. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series IV. SPEAKERS, (Boxes 4-5)
  Announcements, publicity materials, schedules, and other materials relating to visiting speakers. Arranged alphabetically with general files preceding those for individual speakers.
- Series V. GRANTS AND STUDIES, (Box 5)
  Applications, correspondence, questionnaires, and other materials relating to grants for which the program applied and studies in which it participated. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series VI. ORGANIZATIONS AND OTHER WOMEN'S STUDIES PROGRAMS, (Box 5)
  Informational materials, directories, and correspondence relating to women's organizations and Women's Studies programs at other academic institutions. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series VII. MISCELLANEOUS SUBJECT FILES, (Boxes 6-7)
  Materials concerning athletics, coeducation, sexual harrassment, and other subjects. Arranged alphabetically.
Container List
- Series I. Administrative Files and Correspondence
  - Advisory Committee, 1986-1988 (Folder 1.1)
  - Advisory Committee, 1989-1990 (Folder 1.2)
  - Annual Reports, 1977-1989 (Folder 1.3)
  - Annual Reports, 1982-1983 (Folder 1.4)
  - Annual Reports, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.5)
  - Annual Reports, 1990-1994 (Folder 1.6)
  - Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Folder 1.7)
  - Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Folder 1.8)
  - Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Folder 1.9)
  - Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Folder 1.10)
  - Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Folder 1.11)
  - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Folder 1.12)
  - Annual Report, 1998-1999 (Folder 1.13)
  - Annual Report Information, 1998-1999 (Folder 1.14)
  - Annual Report Information, 1999-2000 (Folder 1.15)
  - Annual Report, 2000-2001 (Folder 1.16)
  - Annual Report, 2001-2002 (Folder 1.17)
  - Annual Report, 2003-2004 (Folder 1.18)
  - Annual Report, 2006-2007 (Folder 1.19)
  - Associated Colleges of the Mid-Hudson Area-Women's Studies Academic Coop Program, 1976 (Folder 1.20)
  - Budget Proposals, 1983-1984 (Folder 1.21)
  - Budget Proposals, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.22)
  - Budget Proposals, 1985-1986 (Folder 1.23)
  - Calendar, 1999-2000 (Folder 1.24)
  - Calendar, 2000-2001 (Folder 1.25)
  - Chairperson, undated (Folder 1.26)
  - Conferences, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.27)
  - Conferences, 1985-1986 (Folder 1.28)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Folder 1.29)
  - General Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Folder 1.30)
  - Copies Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Folder 1.31)
  - General Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Folder 1.32)
  - Copies All Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Folder 1.33)
  - General Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Folder 1.34)
  - Correspondence (Copies), 1982-1983 (Folder 1.35)
  - General Communications, 1983-1984 (Folder 1.36)
  - Copies All Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Folder 1.37)
  - Copies All Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.38)
  - General Communications, 1985-1986 (Folder 1.39)
  - Copies All Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Folder 1.40)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Folder 1.41)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Folder 1.42)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Folder 1.43)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Folder 1.44)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Folder 1.45)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Folder 1.46)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Folder 1.47)
  - Official Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Folder 1.48)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Folder 1.49)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Folder 1.50)
  - Crothers, [Diane], undated (Folder 1.51)
  - Crothers, Diane, Correspondence, undated (Folder 1.52)
  - [Crothers Correspondence?], undated (Folder 1.53)
  - Darlington, Beth-Personal - RESTRCTED FILE, 1983-1984 (Folder 1.54)
  - Darlington, Beth-Personal - RESTRCTED FILE, 1984-1985 (Folder 1.55)
  - Department Chairperson, 1982-1983 (Folder 2.1)
  - Department Chairperson, 1984-1985 (Folder 2.2)
  - Department Chairperson, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.3)
  - Development of the Women's Studies Program, 1984-1985 (Folder 2.4)
  - Development of the Women's Studies Program, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.5)
  - Director's Materials, 1998-1999 (Folder 2.6)
  - Faculty and Administrators Interested in Women's Studies, 1981-1982 (Folder 2.7)
  - Faculty Discussion Group, 1982-1983 (Folder 2.8)
  - Faculty Discussion Group, 1983-1984 (Folder 2.9)
  - Faculty Discussion Group, 1984-1985 (Folder 2.10)
  - Faculty Discussion Group, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.11)
  - Faculty Lists, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.12)
  - Faculty and Administrative Lists, undated (Folder 2.13)
  - Freshman Orientation, 1976 (Folder 2.14)
  - General Information, undated (Folder 2.15)
  - Guidelines for Program Membership, undated (Folder 2.16)
  - Informal Committee, undated (Folder 2.17)
  - Information Department Related, 1986 (Folder 2.18)
  - Library Holdings Review, undated (Folder 2.19)
  - Mailing List, 1992-1993 (Folder 2.20)
  - Members/Participants, 1995-1996 (Folder 2.21)
  - Members/Participants, 1996-1997 (Folder 2.22)
  - New England Building (Use), undated (Folder 2.23)
  - Newsletter (incomplete), 1977-1999 (Folder 2.24)
  - Overview Committee, undated (Folder 2.25)
  - Page, Barbara-personal - RESTRCTED FILE, 1985-1986 (Folder 2.26)
  - President's Discretionary Fund, undated (Folder 2.27)
  - Program Review, 1992 (Folder 2.28)
  - Proposal for Grant, undated (Folder 2.29)
  - Self Study, 1992 (Folder 2.30)
  - Staffing, 1983-2003 (Folder 2.31)
  - Steering Committee and Organizational, undated (Folder 2.32)
  - Steering Committee, 1999-2000 (Folder 2.33)
  - Steering Committee, 2000 (Folder 2.34)
  - Steering Committee, 2000-2001 (Folder 2.35)
  - Steering Committee, 2001-2002 (Folder 2.36)
  - Vilardi, Teresa [program coordinator], undated (Folder 2.37)
- Series II. Curriculum
  - Academic Program at Vassar/Intro Course, undated (Folder 2.38)
  - Africana Studies and American Culture Program, undated (Folder 2.39)
  - American Culture, undated (Folder 2.40)
  - American Culture - Civil Rights Course, 1979-1980 (Folder 2.41)
  - Committee on Academic Planning, 1996-1997 (Folder 2.42)
  - Committee on Cirricular Policy (CCP) Information, 1987-1989 (Folder 2.43)
  - Committee on Cirricular Policy (CCP), 1997-1998 (Folder 2.44)
  - Committee on Cirricular Policy (CCP), 1998-99 (Folder 2.45)
  - Committee on Cirricular Policy (CCP), 2000-2001 (Folder 2.46)
  - Course Lists, 1970-1983 (Folder 2.47)
  - Course Lists, 1984-2001 (Folder 2.48)
  - AFRS 212: Women of the World, undated (Folder 2.49)
  - AFRS 264: Black Women in America, undated (Folder 2.50)
  - AFRS/POLI 352: Seminar on Politics in Multicultural Societies, undated (Folder 2.51)
  - AMCL 280: Changing Concept of American Women, undated (Folder 2.52)
  - AMCL 298: Changing American Culture, undated (Folder 2.53)
  - AMCL 298: Women's Place and Women's Work, 1976 (Folder 2.54)
  - AMCL 381: Changing American Culture: Women and American Political Culture, undated (Folder 2.55)
  - AMCL 383: Woman and War, undated (Folder 2.56)
  - ANTH 105: Intro. Anthropology, undated (Folder 2.57)
  - ANTH 214: Ethnography of the Caribbean, undated (Folder 2.58)
  - ANTH 240: Peoples of the Malay World, undated (Folder 2.59)
  - ANTH 280: The Anthropology of Women, undated (Folder 2.60)
  - ANTH 350: Travelling in the World, undated (Folder 2.61)
  - ANTH 351: Linguistic Theory, undated (Folder 2.62)
  - ANTH 362: Male/Female in Anthropological Perspective, undated (Folder 2.63)
  - ANTH 367: Current Themes... The Anthropological Study of Women, undated (Folder 2.64)
  - ART/CLAS 280: Gender and Status in Classical Antiquity, undated (Folder 2.65)
  - ART 310: Women in Classical Art, undated (Folder 2.66)
  - ART 364: Women in the Arts, undated (Folder 2.67)
  - CLCS 262: Work, Gender, and Social Change, undated (Folder 2.68)
  - CLAS 281: Women in Classical Antiquity, undated (Folder 2.69)
  - EDUC 297, undated (Folder 2.70)
  - ENGL 248: Literary Perspectives on Women, undated (Folder 2.71)
  - ENGL 366: Women in the Renaissance, undated (Folder 2.72)
  - ENGL 367: Nondramatic Literature of the Renaissance, undated (Folder 2.73)
  - ENGL 390: Studies in Middle English Literature, undated (Folder 2.74)
  - GEOG 265: Population and Development, undated (Folder 2.75)
  - GEOG 297: Geography of Gender, undated (Folder 2.76)
  - GEOG 365: The Geography of Gender, undated (Folder 2.77)
  - HISP 380: Women and Latin American Literature, undated (Folder 2.78)
  - HIST 250: History of Women in America, undated (Folder 2.79)
  - HIST 261: History of Women in the U.S., undated (Folder 2.80)
  - HIST 280: Women in European History, undated (Folder 2.81)
  - HIST 283: History of European Women to 1800, undated (Folder 2.82)
  - HIST 320: Private Life in Pre-Industrial Europe, undated (Folder 2.83)
  - HIST 383: Women in Latin American History, undated (Folder 2.84)
  - INTD 287: Issues For the Nineties, undated (Folder 2.85)
  - INTD 380: The Victorian Wife, undated (Folder 2.86)
  - INTD 389: Testimony of the Past, undated (Folder 2.87)
  - Medieval/Ren Culture, undated (Folder 2.88)
  - MUSI/WMST 231, undated (Folder 2.89)
  - Music 231, undated (Folder 2.90)
  - PHIL 106: Philosophy, Politics and Society, undated (Folder 2.91)
  - PHIL 250: Feminist Theory, undated (Folder 2.92)
  - PHIL 250: Gender and Power, undated (Folder 2.93)
  - PHIL 283: Feminist Theory, undated (Folder 2.94)
  - PHIL 286: Theory of Emotion, undated (Folder 2.95)
  - PHIL 305: Hannah Arendt, undated (Folder 2.96)
  - PHIL ?: Feminism and Philosophy of the Body, undated (Folder 2.97)
  - POLI 245: Women and American Politics, undated (Folder 2.98)
  - POLI 282: Women in the History of Political Thought, undated (Folder 2.99)
  - POLI 375: The Family, Society and the State, undated (Folder 2.100)
  - PSYC 202: Principles of Development, undated (Folder 2.101)
  - PSYC 205: Social Psychology, undated (Folder 2.102)
  - PSYC 214: Physiological Psychology, undated (Folder 2.103)
  - PSYC 260, undated (Folder 2.104)
  - PSYC 272: Methodsand Issues in Personality and Social Psychology, undated (Folder 2.105)
  - PSYC 297: The Development of Sex Differences, undated (Folder 2.106)
  - PSYC 305: Masculinity and Femininity, undated (Folder 2.107)
  - PSYC 335: Women and Psychopathology, undated (Folder 2.108)
  - PSYC 383: Gender and Psychology, undated (Folder 2.109)
  - RELI 362: Theologies of Human Liberation, undated (Folder 3.1)
  - SOCI 243: Birth, Death and Public Policy, undated (Folder 3.2)
  - SOCI 250: Sex, Gender and Society, undated (Folder 3.3)
  - SOCI 251: Social Change and Revolution, undated (Folder 3.4)
  - SOCI 252: The Family, undated (Folder 3.5)
  - SOCI 284: Comparative Sociology of Revolution, undated (Folder 3.6)
  - SOCI 288: Professions and Power, undated (Folder 3.7)
  - SOCI/STS 342: Women and New Technology, undated (Folder 3.8)
  - SOCI 350: Sociology of Sex Roles, undated (Folder 3.9)
  - SOCI/STS 353: Sociobiology, undated (Folder 3.10)
  - SOCI 355: Sociological Theory/Feminist Social Theory, undated (Folder 3.11)
  - SOCI 380: Sociology of Sex Roles, undated (Folder 3.12)
  - STS 380: Women and New Technology, undated (Folder 3.13)
  - STS ?: Women In Advanced Industrial Society, undated (Folder 3.14)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies (Diane Crothers), 1979 (Folder 3.15)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 1979-1982 (Folder 3.16)
  - Introduction to Women's Studies, 1982-1983 (Folder 3.17)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 1983-1989 (Folder 3.18)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 1990-1995 (Folder 3.19)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 1996-1997 (Folder 3.20)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 1998-2000 (Folder 3.21)
  - WMST 130: Introduction to Women's Studies, 2000-20007, undated (Folder 3.22)
  - [WMST 230]: Feminist Approaches to Science, undated (Folder 3.23)
  - [WMST] 230: Feminist Approaches to Science/Technology, undated (Folder 3.24)
  - WMST 230: [Feminism, Science and Technology], undated (Folder 3.25)
  - WMST 230: Women and Colonialism, undated (Folder 3.26)
  - WMST 230: Women and Film, undated (Folder 3.27)
  - WMST 230: Construction of Gender, undated (Folder 3.28)
  - WMST 240: Construction of Gender, undated (Folder 3.29)
  - WMST 251: Global Feminism, undated (Folder 3.30)
  - WMST 262: Work, Gender and Social Change, undated (Folder 3.31)
  - WMST 280:Women of Color, Fall 1995 (Folder 3.32)
  - WMST/INTL 280: Gender, Post Colonialism and the Visual, undated (Folder 3.33)
  - WMST 297: Constructing American Masculinities, undated (Folder 3.34)
  - WMST 375: Senior Seminar, undated (Folder 3.35)
  - WMST 381: Women, Race and Writing, undated (Folder 3.36)
  - WMST ?: Thinking Lesbian Sex and Politics, undated (Folder 3.37)
  - WMST ?: Post Colonialism and Third World Feminsm, undated (Folder 3.38)
  - Curriculum Change, 1994-1995 (Folder 3.39)
  - Curriculum Change, 1995-1996 (Folder 3.40)
  - Field Work, undated (Folder 3.41)
  - Field Work, undated (Folder 3.42)
  - Field Work, undated (Folder 3.43)
  - Handbook, undated (Folder 3.44)
  - Handbook Corrections, undated (Folder 3.45)
  - Handbook, 1992-1993 (Folder 3.46)
  - Honors Criteria, 1995-2002 (Folder 3.47)
  - Introduction to Women's Studies, undated (Folder 3.48)
  - Shirley Johnson (Gender and Work), undated (Folder 3.49)
  - Misc. Course Material, undated (Folder 3.50)
  - Proposed Courses, undated (Folder 3.51)
  - Senior Theses, undated (Folder 3.52)
  - Study Trip, 1998 (Folder 3.53)
- Series III. Events
  - "American Family" Symposium, 1980 (Folder 3.54)
  - Berkshire Conference, undated (Folder 3.55)
  - Bishop Celebration, 1980 (Folder 3.56)
  - Conference on Worldwide Education for Women, 1987 (Folder 3.57)
  - Coalition, 1985 (Folder 3.58)
  - Coalition Dinner, 1996 (Folder 3.59)
  - Coalition Dinner, 1997-1998 (Folder 3.60)
  - Coalition Dinner, 1998-1999 (Folder 3.61)
  - Coalition Dinner, 2000-2001 (Folder 3.62)
  - Coalition Dinner, 2001-2002 (Folder 3.63)
  - Conferences, 1979-1980 (Folder 3.64)
  - Conferences, 1995-1996 (Folder 3.65)
  - Conferences, Newsletters, 1988 (Folder 3.66)
  - Conferences Women's Studies Faculty, 1985 (Folder 3.67)
  - Dean Daniels, undated (Folder 3.68)
  - Dinner - May 4th, undated (Folder 3.69)
  - End of Semester Dinner, 1998-1999 (Folder 3.70)
  - End of Semester Dinner, 1999 December 9 (Folder 3.71)
  - End of Semester Dinner, 2000 May 25 (Folder 3.72)
  - Events - Misc, undated (Folder 3.73)
  - Film, undated (Folder 3.74)
  - Film Festival, 1982-1983 (Folder 3.75)
  - Films, undated (Folder 3.76)
  - Films, 1982-1983 (Folder 3.77)
  - Films, 1985-1986 (Folder 3.78)
  - Films/Possible Projects, undated (Folder 3.79)
  - First Fridays, 1988 (Folder 3.80)
  - First Friday, 1992-1993 (Folder 3.81)
  - First Friday, 1993-1994 (Folder 3.82)
  - First Fridays, 1994-1995 (Folder 3.83)
  - First Fridays, 1995-1996 (Folder 3.84)
  - First Friday, 1999-2000 (Folder 3.85)
  - First Friday, 2000-2001 (Folder 3.86)
  - First Friday, 2001-2002 (Folder 3.87)
  - First Friday Announcements of WMST Sponsored Events, 1996-1997 (Folder 3.88)
  - Global Feminisms Conference, 1994, 1997 (Folder 3.89)
  - Hunger Symposium, 1986 (Folder 3.90)
  - Nancy Milford - Testimony of the Past, undated (Folder 3.91)
  - National Women's Studies Association Conference, 1998-1999 (Folder 3.92)
  - National Women's Studies Association Conference, 2000 (Folder 3.93)
  - New Faculty Reception, 1997-1998 (Folder 3.94)
  - New Faculty Reception, 1998-1999 (Folder 3.95)
  - New Faculty Reception, 1999-2000 (Folder 3.96)
  - New Faculty Reception, 2000-2001 (Folder 3.97)
  - New Faculty Reception, 2001-2002 (Folder 3.98)
  - Pornography (College), 1985 (Folder 4.1)
  - Pornography -- Women Against, undated (Folder 4.2)
  - Potluck Dinner, 2000 December 7 (Folder 4.3)
  - Retreat File, 1993-1994 (Folder 4.4)
  - Retreat, 1994-1995 (Folder 4.5)
  - Retreat, 1995-1996 (Folder 4.6)
  - Retreat, 1998-1999 (Folder 4.7)
  - Seven College Conference, 1988 (Folder 4.8)
  - Spring Series Images and Gender, 1986 (Folder 4.9)
  - Symposium on Empowerment International Perspectives, 1987 (Folder 4.10)
  - Vassar Women's Weekend, 1977 (Folder 4.11)
  - Wednesday Lunches, undated (Folder 4.12)
  - Women and Music, undated (Folder 4.13)
  - Women's Coalition, 1994-1995 (Folder 4.14)
  - Women's Studies and International Studies Seminars/Symposiums, undated (Folder 4.15)
  - Women's Weekend, undated (Folder 4.16)
  - Working it Out, October 7 (Folder 4.17)
- Series IV. Speakers
  - Lectures and Lecturers, 1982-1983 (Folder 4.18)
  - Lectures and Lecturers, 1983-1984 (Folder 4.19)
  - Lectures and Lecturers, 1984-1985 (Folder 4.20)
  - Lectures and Lecturers, 1985-1986 (Folder 4.21)
  - Past Speakers and Guest Lecturers, undated (Folder 4.22)
  - Speakers - Misc., undated (Folder 4.23)
  - Support of Speakers, undated (Folder 4.24)
  - Support of Speakers, 1998-1999 (Folder 4.25)
  - Support of Speakers, 1999-2000 (Folder 4.26)
  - Aisenberg, Nadya, undated (Folder 4.27)
  - Avery, Byllye, 1994 October 26 (Folder 4.28)
  - Baym, Nina, undated (Folder 4.29)
  - Becker, Carol, 1999 April 14 (Folder 4.30)
  - Berresford, Susan V., 1998 November 12 (Folder 4.31)
  - Brodo, Susan, 1998 February 26 (Folder 4.32)
  - Brody, Jennifer, 1999 September 23 (Folder 4.33)
  - Brown, Elaine, undated (Folder 4.34)
  - Bunch, Charlotte, undated (Folder 4.35)
  - Butalia, Pankaj, 1995 November 2 (Folder 4.36)
  - Butler, Octavia, 1997 April (Folder 4.37)
  - Carby, Hazel, 2000 September 13 (Folder 4.38)
  - Chollet Towdin, Jacqueline, undated (Folder 4.39)
  - Cixous, [Helene], undated (Folder 4.40)
  - Daniels, Elizabeth, undated (Folder 4.41)
  - Daniels, Kate, undated (Folder 4.42)
  - Davies, Carol Boyce, 2002 February 28 (Folder 4.43)
  - Davis, Natalie Zemon, undated (Folder 4.44)
  - Dubois, Ellen, 1998 October 5 (Folder 4.45)
  - Elshtain, Jean, undated (Folder 4.46)
  - Enloe, Cynthia, undated (Folder 4.47)
  - Enloe, Cynthia, 1995 April 6 (Folder 4.48)
  - Enloe, Cynthia, 1998 October 29 (Folder 4.49)
  - Fairstein, Linda, 2000 February (Folder 4.50)
  - Farrell-Smith, Janet, undated (Folder 4.51)
  - Feigin, Brenda, 2000 October 4 (Folder 4.52)
  - Ferrell, Carolyn, 1999 October 16 (Folder 4.53)
  - Gachukia, Eddah, undated (Folder 4.54)
  - Garrett, Angelica, and Spaulding, Frances, 1984-1985 (Folder 4.55)
  - Gillespie, Marcia, 1998 November 18 (Folder 4.56)
  - Guggenheimer, Elinor, undated (Folder 4.57)
  - Guy-Sheftall, Beverley, undated (Folder 4.58)
  - Hartmann, Heidi, 1998 April 13 (Folder 4.59)
  - Hartsock, Nancy, undated (Folder 4.60)
  - Hawkins, Harriet, undated (Folder 4.61)
  - Held, Virginia, undated (Folder 4.62)
  - Hite, Molly, 2000 February 3 (Folder 4.63)
  - Hooks, Bell, undated (Folder 4.64)
  - Hornbacher, Marya, 1999 April 22 (Folder 4.65)
  - Gurnsey, Jane Howard, 2000 March 23 (Folder 4.66)
  - Howe, Florence, undated (Folder 4.67)
  - Howe, Florence, undated (Folder 4.68)
  - Kaplan, Cora, undated (Folder 4.69)
  - Fox Keller, Evelyn, undated (Folder 4.70)
  - Kimmel, Michael, 1996 (Folder 4.71)
  - Kim-Gibson, Dai Sil, 1999 November 10 (Folder 4.72)
  - Klein, Ethel, undated (Folder 4.73)
  - Kurgweil, Edith, undated (Folder 4.74)
  - Layne, Linda, undated (Folder 4.75)
  - Lerner, Gerda, undated (Folder 4.76)
  - Lerner, Gerda, undated (Folder 4.77)
  - Littleton, Christine, undated (Folder 4.78)
  - Lubiano, Waheema, 1995 October 31 (Folder 4.79)
  - Lugones, Maria, 1994 September 22 (Folder 4.80)
  - Maso, Carole, 1999 September 14 (Folder 4.81)
  - McDonough, Yona, 1999 November 10 (Folder 4.82)
  - Mohanty, Chandra, undated (Folder 4.83)
  - Moreau, Thirese, undated (Folder 4.84)
  - Nicholson, Linda, undated (Folder 4.85)
  - Painter, Nell, 1998 September 17 (Folder 4.86)
  - Pateman, Carole, undated (Folder 4.87)
  - Pemberton, Gayle, 1995 October 24 (Folder 4.88)
  - Pollitt, Katha, undated (Folder 4.89)
  - Sawiki, Jana, undated (Folder 4.90)
  - Schmukler, Beatriz Elba, undated (Folder 4.91)
  - Seaman, Barbara, 1997 February 6 (Folder 5.1)
  - Sen, Gita, undated (Folder 5.2)
  - Sharma, Renu, and Upreti, Tara, 2001 February 12 (Folder 5.3)
  - Shiva, Vandana, undated (Folder 5.4)
  - Shiva, Vandana, 1998 February 25 (Folder 5.5)
  - Snitow, Ann, undated (Folder 5.6)
  - Somerville, Siobhan, 2001 April 2 (Folder 5.7)
  - Spelman, Eliz V., undated (Folder 5.8)
  - Stansell, Christine, 2000 November 13 (Folder 5.9)
  - Stimpson, Catherine, undated (Folder 5.10)
  - Tajima Creef, Elena, 1998 November 3 (Folder 5.11)
  - Toledo, Elizabeth, 1999 April 6 (Folder 5.12)
  - Vollp, Leti, 2001 September 17 (Folder 5.13)
  - Wachman, Gay, 2002 April 4 (Folder 5.14)
  - Warren, Kay B., undated (Folder 5.15)
  - Wasserstein, Wendy, 1998-1999 (Folder 5.16)
  - Weber, Saskia, 1999 December 6 (Folder 5.17)
  - Westenhoefer, Suzanne, 2000 April 2 (Folder 5.18)
  - Speakers - Misc., undated (Folder 5.19)
- Series V. Grants and Studies
  - Classroom Climate Study - Cornelius, Gray, Constantinople, undated (Folder 5.20)
  - Global Feminisms Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Folder 5.21)
  - Grants, 1995-1996 (Folder 5.22)
  - Huber Foundation, 1990 (Folder 5.23)